Don't let go.
Gravity is a science fiction, thriller, drama film directed by Alfonso Cuarón.
Ryan Stone, a brilliant medical engineer, is on her first Shuttle mission, with veteran
astronaut Matt Kowalski in command of his last flight before retiring.
But on a seemingly routine spacewalk, disaster strikes.
The Shuttle is destroyed, leaving Stone and Kowalski completely alone-tethered to
nothing but each other and spiraling out into the blackness of space.
The deafening silence tells them they have lost any
link to Earth and any chance for rescue.
As fear turns to panic, every gulp of air eats
away at what little oxygen is left.
But the only way home may be to go further out into
the terrifying expanse of space.
Ryan Stone, played by Sandra Bullock.
Matt Kowalski, played by George Clooney.
Mission Control (voice), played by Ed Harris.
Aningaaq (voice), played by Orto Ignatiussen.
Shariff (voice), played by Phaldut Sharma.
Explorer Captain (voice), played by Amy Warren.
Gravity is a 2013 science fiction thriller film directed by Alfonso
Cuarón, who also co-wrote, co-edited, and produced the film.
It stars Sandra Bullock and George Clooney as American astronauts who attempt to
return to Earth after the destruction of their Space Shuttle in orbit.
Cuarón wrote the screenplay with his son Jonás and attempted
to develop the film at Universal Pictures.
Later, the distribution rights were acquired by Warner Bros.
David Heyman, who previously worked with Cuarón on Harry Potter and the
Prisoner of Azkaban (2004), produced the film with him.
Gravity was produced entirely in the United Kingdom, where British visual effects company Framestore spent more
than three years creating most of the film's visual effects, which involve over 80 of its 91 minutes.
Gravity opened the 70th Venice International Film Festival on August 28, 2013, and had its
North American premiere three days later at the Telluride Film Festival.
Upon its release, Gravity was met with widespread critical acclaim, with high
praise for its direction, visuals, cinematography, acting, and score.
Considered one of the best films of 2013, it appeared on numerous critics' year-end lists, and was
selected by the American Film Institute in their annual Movies of the Year list.
The film became the eighth-highest-grossing film of the year with a worldwide gross of
over $723 million, against a production budget of around $100 million.
Gravity received a leading 10 nominations at the 86th Academy Awards, including Best Picture and Best
Actress (for Bullock), and won a leading seven awards, including Best Director (for Cuarón).
At the 67th British Academy Film Awards, the film received a leading 11 nominations, including Best Film and Best Actress in a
Leading Role (for Bullock), and won a leading 6 awards, including Outstanding British Film and Best Director (for Cuarón).
It also received 4 nominations at the 71st Golden Globe Awards, including Best Motion Picture – Drama and
Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama (for Bullock), with Cuarón winning Best Director.
At the 19th Critics' Choice Awards, the film received 10 nominations, including Best Picture and Best Actress (for Bullock), and won a leading
seven awards, including Best Sci-Fi/Horror Movie, Best Director (for Cuarón) and Best Actress in an Action Movie (for Bullock).
Bullock also received a nomination for the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Leading
Role, while the film won the 2013 Ray Bradbury Award, and the 2014 Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation.
Since its release, it has been cited as among the best
films of the 2010s and the 21st century.
The film explores themes of space mission, melancholy, loss, space, astronaut.
The tone is uplifting and emotional and thought_provoking.